YOUNGSUN KIM

Madison, WI sundrop03@gmail.com \(\display +1 (608) 733-7373 https://sundrop03.github.io

SUMMARY

Dedicated academic with extensive experience in insurance consulting, risk management, and business analytics. Ongoing research explores financial decision-making under regulatory changes and natural hazards, using insurance companies as a model. Proven success in developing and teaching courses in financial mathematics, risk management, and insurance theory, effectively bridging theoretical concepts with practical applications. Committed to fostering student learning with interactive teaching methods and ongoing, supportive feedback.

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin-Madison
Ph.D. in Business (Insurance Economics and Actuarial Analytics)

Georgia State University
M.S. in Actuarial Science
M.S. in Risk Management and Insurance

Korea University
B.A. in Public Administration (Minor: Economics)

Madison, WI
August 2024

August 2024

May 2015

May 2015

Korea University
B.A. in Public Administration (Minor: Economics)

WORKING PAPERS

Kim, Y. and Bauer, D. (2023). Transfer Learning in the Actuarial Domain: Foundations and Applications, Submitted

Kim, Y. (2023). Insurance Agency Locations in Milwaukee: Insights from New Data and Agency Differentiation, Submitted

Kim, Y. and Bauer, D. (2024). Cross-subsidization in the Personal Insurance Markets, Working paper

TEACHING ACTIVITIES

Actuarial Science Methods II (ACT SCI 301)

Madison, WI

Lecturer (SA) - Undergraduate course

August 2020 - May 2024

· Developed and delivered two 75-minute lectures per week on financial mathematics, aimed at enhancing students' knowledge of mathematical tools for quantitatively assessing financial risk.

Machine Learning for Business Analytics (GB 656)

Madison, WI

Teaching Assistant - Master's course

August 2021 - December 2023

· Introduced machine learning foundations and methods for business applications, evaluated assignments, and coached 130+ students in R and Python for predictive and financial modeling, offering office hours to support coding skills and Kaggle competition preparation.

Business Analytics II (GB 307)

Madison, WI

Teaching Assistant - Undergraduate course

August 2019 - May 2020

· Emphasized hands-on experience with analytic methodologies in predictive and prescriptive analytics, leading two weekly 50-minute sessions on quantitative analysis and data manipulation using Excel and Access.

Business Analytics I (GB 306)

Madison, WI

Teaching Assistant - Undergraduate course

August 2018 - May 2019

· Led weekly 50-minute sessions to help develop quantitative intuition through hands-on Excel work, focusing on hypothesis testing, regression, simulation, statistical literacy, and effective data communication.

PRESENTATIONS

The 58th Actuarial Research Conference

Des Moines, IA

Persistence of Insurance Redlining: Exploring distribution of insurance agencies and implications

August 2023

The 57th Actuarial Research Conference

Champaign, IL

Transfer Learning in Actuarial Science: Primer and Applications

August 2022

HONORS & REWARDS

Actuarial Research Conference Honorable Mention	2023
Wisconsin School of Business Travel Award	2022, 2023
Wisconsin School of Business Distinguished Teaching Award	2020, 2021, 2022, 2023
Wisconsin School of Business Graduate Scholarship	2018 - 2022

WORKSHOPS & CONFERENCES

Causal Inference - hosted by American Risk and Insurance Association (ARIA)	December 2021
Allied Social Science Associations (ASSA)/American Economic Association (AEA) Annual Meeting	January 2021
World Risk & Insurance Economics Congress - hosted by ARIA	August 2020
Financial Economics of Insurance - hosted by Princeton University	June 2020

AFFILIATIONS & MEMBERSHIPS

Member - American Risk and Insurance Association (ARIA)

2021 – Present

REVIEWER SERVICE

Referee - Journal of Risk and Insurance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Samsung Fire & Marine Insurance

Seoul, Korea *July 2021*

Graduate Intern

- · Analyzed the current risk model and presented optimal risk capital management strategies to the Chief Actuary.
- · Demonstrated flexibility with machine learning and explored its feasibility in risk rate analysis, presenting findings to leadership.

Willis Towers Watson

Actuarial Analyst

Seoul, Korea

December 2015 - May 2018

- · Implemented economic capital modeling in a dynamic financial analysis project for a large P&C insurer.
- · Served as the primary point of contact for communication with P&C insurers and regulatory authorities in the region. Additionally, led a proof of concept to automate the client's legacy system, aligning it with regulatory changes.
- · Led solution sales to P&C insurers and served as the primary instructor for professional training sessions. Organized the inaugural industry-wide seminar, gathering insurance professionals and regulators to enhance company presence in the region.
- · Conducted analyses on an insurer's claims and reserve assumptions as part of a Best Estimate analysis project. Additionally, updated and analyzed actuarial assumptions to compare the Embedded Value (EV) and appraisal value of an insurer.

Samjung ShippingSeoul, KoreaOperations AssistantJanuary 2011 - December 2012

- · Performed market analysis and updated the availability of optimal vessels in the open market to inform procurement decisions.
- · Reviewed and processed extra insurance premiums for cargoes carried by over-aged vessels.

CERTIFICATIONS AND EXAMS

Society of Actuaries

- · Passed Exam P, Exam FM, and Exam IFM
- · Received transition credit for Exam SRM
- · Passed the Pre-Actuarial Foundations (PAF) module
- · Completed all VEE credits

Chartered Property Casualty Underwriter (CPCU)

· Passed Exam 540: Finance and Accounting for Insurance Professionals

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Software MS Office Suite and QGIS Programming R, Python, and VBA

Actuarial Software MoSes, RiskAgility FM, Emblem, Igloo, and ResQ